{
    "title": "Basics of Coding Quiz",
    "total": 29,
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "What is Scratch?",
            "options": [
                "A video game made by high school students",
                "Itchy skin is an irritating sensation that makes you want to scratch",
                "Scratch is a programming tool created by the students of MIT that is used to learn the basics of coding.",
                "An online encyclopedia meant for middle schoolers"
            ],
            "score": 1,
            "correctAnswerIndex": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Which way does the x-axis move?",
            "options": [
                "Up and down",
                "Right & Left",
                "Diagonally",
                "It doesn’t move"
            ],
            "score": 3,
            "correctAnswerIndex": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "What are Conditional Statements?",
            "options": [
                "A statement that runs no matter what is true",
                "A statement that’s only found in the code for games",
                "A statement that’s only found in one coding language",
                "A set of rules performed if a certain condition is met (tells a program to run different actions based on if a specific condition is true or false)"
            ],
            "score": 2,
            "correctAnswerIndex": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "What are variables?",
            "options": [
                "A variable is a name used to store information (used to reference and manipulate in a computer program)",
                "A part of a math equation that has alphabets substituted for numbers",
                "Anything that can change or be changed within an experiment",
                "Any characteristic, number, or quantity that can be measured or counted"
            ],
            "score": 1,
            "correctAnswerIndex": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "What are the two main types of loops called?",
            "options": [
                "Here & There",
                "While & For",
                "In & Out",
                "Left & Right"
            ],
            "score": 3,
            "correctAnswerIndex": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "What are wait-blocks?",
            "options": [
                "Lines outside grocery stores",
                "They skip the next block",
                "They repeat a behavior forever",
                "Control block that allows the cat to wait for a given amount of time"
            ],
            "score": 1,
            "correctAnswerIndex": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "What are If-Else Statements?",
            "options": [
                "Used to check whether the given condition is true or false.",
                "Conditionals describe the result of a certain condition",
                "This statement runs a block of code “if” a specific condition is true. “Else” is used to run a block of code if the specific condition is false",
                "An alternative statement that is executed if the result of a previous test condition"
            ],
            "score": 2,
            "correctAnswerIndex": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "What are Loops?",
            "options": [
                "A closed curve whose initial and final points coincide in a fixed point known as the basepoint.",
                "A loop is a structure that repeats instructions until a condition is met",
                "A shape produced by a curve that bends around and crosses itself",
                "A repeating section of sound material"
            ],
            "score": 2,
            "correctAnswerIndex": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "What way does the y-axis move?",
            "options": [
                "Up & down",
                "Left & Right",
                "In & Out",
                "Diagonally"
            ],
            "score": 3,
            "correctAnswerIndex": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "What is coding?",
            "options": [
                "A game to give instructions",
                "A number to assign different computers",
                "All the standards to teach technology in the classroom",
                "Coding is the computer language used to develop apps, websites, and software"
            ],
            "score": 3,
            "correctAnswerIndex": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "What are sensors?",
            "options": [
                "A device which detects or measures a physical property and records, indicates, or otherwise responds to it",
                "A device for recording an image of an object on a light-sensitive surface",
                "A category of blocks used to detect things using the different senses",
                "An enclosed compartment, as in a kitchen range, for cooking and heating food"
            ],
            "score": 1,
            "correctAnswerIndex": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "How does a code work?",
            "options": [
                "It organizes viruses",
                "It tells your computer what to do",
                "It doesn't work at all",
                "It is a random number"
            ],
            "score": 2,
            "correctAnswerIndex": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "What word is strongly related to code?",
            "options": [
                "Commands",
                "Summary",
                "Bad grades",
                "None"
            ],
            "score": 2,
            "correctAnswerIndex": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following careers are related to coding?",
            "options": [
                "Doctor",
                "Construction Worker",
                "Engineering",
                "Police Officer"
            ],
            "score": 3,
            "correctAnswerIndex": 2
        }
    ]
}
